QUANG NGUYEN

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (IOS & WEB)

SUMMARY

Self-taught software developer based in Orange County, California, specialized in building and designing full-stack web apps and high-performance native apps for mobile devices. 2 years of experience in working with clients to develop and transform ideas into real-world applications that satisfy the consumer's needs.

SKILLS

- · Languages: Swift, Python, Javascript, C#.
- Front-End: HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, AJAX.
 - Back-End: Django, Node.js.
- Databases: SQLite, MySQL, Firebase, Core Data.
 Apple Frameworks: UIKit, SwiftUI, Core
 Location, MapKit, Grand Central Dispatch (CGD).

GET IN TOUCH

Mobile: (714) 585-3564 Email: wan15112001@gmail.com GitHub: github.com/quangnguyen17 Portfolio: quangnguyen17.github.io/ LinkedIn: @quangnguyen2001

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Doogy!

Social Platform - (Febuary 2020 - Present)

- A place where dog enthusiasts can be who they are and find thousands of dog pictures being fetched from a public API in which hosts one of the biggest collections of open source dog pictures.
- · API: https://dog.ceo/dog-api/
- · Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, iQuery & Javascript, AJAX.
- · Back-End: Python & Django.
- · Database: SQLite.
- See Project: http://13.52.102.43/

Find Waldo

Game - (January 2020 - Present)

- · An open-source project
- Re-inventing the classic 'Find Waldo' game on the web!
- Technologies: HTML5, CSS3 & Animations, Bootstrap, jQuery & Javascript.
- See Project: https://quangnguyen17.github.io/find-waldo/

Kinh Thánh BD2011

Book - (June 2018 - July 2018)

- · A Bible App.
- Technologies: Swift, UIKit, Grand Central Dispatch (GCD).
- · Database: Core Data, Firebase.
- <u>See Project</u>: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/kinh-th%C3%A1nh-bd2011/id1405782410

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance iOS Developer

Self-Employed - (June 2017 - Present)

- Enthusiastic developer who's eager to learn new technologies and apply it to build real world applications,
- · Contracted several projects.
- · Hired to build and fix applications in productions by companies.

iOS Contractor

Vietnamese Bible Association - (June 2018 - July 2018)

- · Designed and developed a bible app in Swift.
- Built using UIKit, used Core Data as the persistent storage and Firebase for storing and retrieving data.
- Implemented [Grand Central Dispatch (GCD) to make calls to the server asynchronously in the background to maintain a responsive and stateful user experience.

EDUCATION

Coding Dojo - Full Stack Web Development (January 2020 - May 2020)

Self-Taught - iOS Development (April 2017 - Present)

Westminster High School - HS Diploma (April 2017 - June 2019)